<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-14T10:28:58-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Kaffeinated Kodemonkey</title><subtitle>Accessibility Driven Development, website Design that meets Accessibility Standards.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Digital Advertising for Local Businesses</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/advertising/Digital_Advertising-Local-Business.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Advertising for Local Businesses" /><published>2018-08-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-08-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/advertising/Digital_Advertising-Local-Business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/advertising/Digital_Advertising-Local-Business.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Blog/DigitalAdvertisingLocalBusiness/Feature-Image.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital Advertising Logo&quot; class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Digital Advertising for Local Businesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, we have seen traditional advertising take the backseat for modern technology. Traditional media companies are now switching their direction and adopting digital, but why? Because there is an extremely large market interested in digital advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital advertising spend is set to grow from $83 billion this year to $129+ billion &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vendasta.com/blog/digital-advertising-statistics&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;by 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Blog/DigitalAdvertisingLocalBusiness/giphy-downsized-300x158.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Joe in Shock&quot; style=&quot;width: 20%;&quot; class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;WOW!&lt;/span&gt; That’s a lot of money. Statistics like this show us just how high the demand is for digital advertising solutions; and just how successful digital advertising can be in terms of acquiring new customers for local businesses. Digital advertising is becoming a necessary addition to every local businesses toolkit!&amp;lt;?p&amp;gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can local businesses leverage digital advertising to acquire new customers, revenue and generate massive online engagement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have the foundation that every local business needs to succeed in the realm of digital advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How Does Digital Advertising Help a Local Business?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital advertising increases awareness—it’s that simple. Digital advertising consists of a range of services, all of which work to promote a business online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more businesses are increasing the amount that they spend on digital advertising, and experts like Jamie Turner suggest digital advertising on social platforms is well worth the spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If I were to provide one tip to people who are using social media, it would be this — don’t be afraid of paying for social media reach and clicks.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;– Jamie Turner, &lt;cite title=&quot;Source Title&quot;&gt;60secondmarketer.com&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about digital advertising is that results can be easily monitored and ROI can be easily tracked. You probably don’t want to be spending lotsa money without some proof of performance right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With traditional media channels, there is sometimes no way of tracking the effectiveness of an advertisement in terms of advanced data analytics. With digital advertising, companies like Google and Facebook allow users to access advanced analytics. This way local businesses know that their money is being well spent and that the digital advertisements are positively impacting their storefront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When determining the success of an ad, the important factors will differ case by case. For the most part, the success of an ad lies in the indicators listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ROI indicators/measures of a successful campaign:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-ul&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impressions&lt;/strong&gt;: the actual # of views on an advertisement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clicks&lt;/strong&gt;: the actual # of direct clicks on the advertisement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engagements&lt;/strong&gt;: Social &amp;amp; landing page clicks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;: In most cases, results come in the form of a phone call or a store visit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Best Places to Advertise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Blog/DigitalAdvertisingLocalBusiness/2000px-Google__G__Logo.svg_-150x150.png&quot; alt=&quot;Social Media Logo&quot; style=&quot;width: 10%;&quot; class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm img-responsive pull-right&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Blog/DigitalAdvertisingLocalBusiness/1000px-F_icon.svg_-150x150.png&quot; alt=&quot;Social Media Logo&quot; style=&quot;width: 10%;&quot; class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-md-12&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;small text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google &amp;amp; Facebook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With digital advertising, not only is a local business visible online, but they are visible to the right people online. Platforms like Facebook and Google allow for advanced targeting, which puts a local business in front of consumers who are more likely to convert into a sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, Google and Facebook accounted for roughly 60 percent of ad spend in 2017!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Blog/DigitalAdvertisingLocalBusiness/2000px-Google__G__Logo.svg_-300x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Logo&quot; style=&quot;width: 20%;&quot; class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm img-responsive&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why Google?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reach&lt;/strong&gt;: Google is the largest search network in the world, and consumers are using Google every single day to search for local businesses. Utilizing Google’s massive network capabilities, digital advertisers are able to find ideal prospects and get in front of users looking for their products/services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the age of digital, people are not looking at TV commercials or listening to radio ads to find a local business, they are searching for a service and then locating your business online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internetlivestats.com/google-search-statistics/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;3.5 Billion Google searches conducted every single day&lt;/a&gt;, customers are looking for local businesses and businesses should want to be on Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;: Google allows the local advertiser to spend whatever they want, whenever they want. With flexible options for ad spend, advertisers are able to test what works and what doesn’t work for a business. Spend a bit, wait to see how the campaign performs, and then reinvest in larger budgets for greater prospect reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Blog/DigitalAdvertisingLocalBusiness/1000px-F_icon.svg_-300x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook Logo&quot; style=&quot;width: 20%;&quot; class=&quot;hidden-xs hidden-sm img-responsive&quot; /&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Why Facebook?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience&lt;/strong&gt;: The audience on Facebook includes 1.32 billion daily active users (DAUs) on average, at an increase of 17% year-over-year. As a local business, you simply cannot ignore the fact that Facebook is likely an intersection in which you can find prospective customers. If the daily average users stat doesn’t have you convinced then let’s talk about how often social media is being used. The average person spends nearly 35 minutes everyday JUST on Facebook, according to a recent study by Mediakix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing to take away it is that the audience on Facebook is MASSIVE, and they are on Facebook a &lt;span class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Targeting: Facebook Ad targeting is a marketer’s dream. Facebook allows the ability to focus on users so microscopically that you can basically become a bit of a digital stalker (in a good way?). Target users by their interests, behaviours, age, gender, location, and really anything that their Facebook profile may reveal about them including job title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Facebook algorithm has brought about changes to the local advertising landscape, but it remains one of the best environments for local businesses to get the word out about themselves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging these 2 platforms, every local business can easily take their advertising game to the next level, and begin to rake in new revenue—with the data to back their investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Advertising" /><summary type="html">Digital Advertising for Local Businesses In recent years, we have seen traditional advertising take the backseat for modern technology. Traditional media companies are now switching their direction and adopting digital, but why? Because there is an extremely large market interested in digital advertising. Digital advertising spend is set to grow from $83 billion this year to $129+ billion by 2021. WOW! That’s a lot of money. Statistics like this show us just how high the demand is for digital advertising solutions; and just how successful digital advertising can be in terms of acquiring new customers for local businesses. Digital advertising is becoming a necessary addition to every local businesses toolkit!&amp;lt;?p&amp;gt; So how can local businesses leverage digital advertising to acquire new customers, revenue and generate massive online engagement? We have the foundation that every local business needs to succeed in the realm of digital advertising. But first, How Does Digital Advertising Help a Local Business? Digital advertising increases awareness—it’s that simple. Digital advertising consists of a range of services, all of which work to promote a business online. More and more businesses are increasing the amount that they spend on digital advertising, and experts like Jamie Turner suggest digital advertising on social platforms is well worth the spend. “If I were to provide one tip to people who are using social media, it would be this — don’t be afraid of paying for social media reach and clicks.” – Jamie Turner, 60secondmarketer.com The best part about digital advertising is that results can be easily monitored and ROI can be easily tracked. You probably don’t want to be spending lotsa money without some proof of performance right? With traditional media channels, there is sometimes no way of tracking the effectiveness of an advertisement in terms of advanced data analytics. With digital advertising, companies like Google and Facebook allow users to access advanced analytics. This way local businesses know that their money is being well spent and that the digital advertisements are positively impacting their storefront. When determining the success of an ad, the important factors will differ case by case. For the most part, the success of an ad lies in the indicators listed below. ROI indicators/measures of a successful campaign: Impressions: the actual # of views on an advertisement Clicks: the actual # of direct clicks on the advertisement Engagements: Social &amp;amp; landing page clicks Results: In most cases, results come in the form of a phone call or a store visit. The Best Places to Advertise Google &amp;amp; Facebook &amp;nbsp; With digital advertising, not only is a local business visible online, but they are visible to the right people online. Platforms like Facebook and Google allow for advanced targeting, which puts a local business in front of consumers who are more likely to convert into a sale. Plus, Google and Facebook accounted for roughly 60 percent of ad spend in 2017! Why Google? Reach: Google is the largest search network in the world, and consumers are using Google every single day to search for local businesses. Utilizing Google’s massive network capabilities, digital advertisers are able to find ideal prospects and get in front of users looking for their products/services. In the age of digital, people are not looking at TV commercials or listening to radio ads to find a local business, they are searching for a service and then locating your business online. With 3.5 Billion Google searches conducted every single day, customers are looking for local businesses and businesses should want to be on Google. Flexibility: Google allows the local advertiser to spend whatever they want, whenever they want. With flexible options for ad spend, advertisers are able to test what works and what doesn’t work for a business. Spend a bit, wait to see how the campaign performs, and then reinvest in larger budgets for greater prospect reach. Why Facebook? Audience: The audience on Facebook includes 1.32 billion daily active users (DAUs) on average, at an increase of 17% year-over-year. As a local business, you simply cannot ignore the fact that Facebook is likely an intersection in which you can find prospective customers. If the daily average users stat doesn’t have you convinced then let’s talk about how often social media is being used. The average person spends nearly 35 minutes everyday JUST on Facebook, according to a recent study by Mediakix. If there is one thing to take away it is that the audience on Facebook is MASSIVE, and they are on Facebook a LOT. Targeting: Facebook Ad targeting is a marketer’s dream. Facebook allows the ability to focus on users so microscopically that you can basically become a bit of a digital stalker (in a good way?). Target users by their interests, behaviours, age, gender, location, and really anything that their Facebook profile may reveal about them including job title. The Facebook algorithm has brought about changes to the local advertising landscape, but it remains one of the best environments for local businesses to get the word out about themselves! Conclusion By leveraging these 2 platforms, every local business can easily take their advertising game to the next level, and begin to rake in new revenue—with the data to back their investment. &amp;nbsp;</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Enhanced-SEO.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Native Advertising</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/advertising/Native-Advertising.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Native Advertising" /><published>2018-07-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/advertising/Native-Advertising</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/advertising/Native-Advertising.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Native-Ad-FI.png&quot; alt=&quot;Native Advertising&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Native Advertising&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is native advertising?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native advertising is an advertising tactic that is earning increased usage as either a complement to, or an alternative for, display advertising. It’s also a concept that plagues much of the digital marketing community with varying degrees of confusion. Luckily for you, I’ll get into the gritty details on this new supplementary and possibly replacement advertising service a little more below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is Native Advertising?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native advertising is essentially a play on traditional display advertising (via banners and pop-ups), where advertisers have the opportunity to showcase their ads within the other content that publishing companies are already pushing out (be it Facebook or your local newspaper’s site).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advertisers contribute either a “sponsored”, a “promoted”, or a “branded” piece of content that generally still creates value for the reader, while also subtly alluding-to or referencing the brand that is paying to have it shown. This allows companies to advertise for themselves in a way that truly creates value for the consumer, while mitigating the frustrations that are often associated with pop-ups and banners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need some examples? So did I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Examples of Native Advertising&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the platform it’s appearing on, native advertising can look and display differently. Lets cover a couple common examples you may see (or provide) on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of Native Advertising on Facebook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is one of the most popular websites in the world, so it makes sense that native advertising is a popular appearance on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/native-advertising/Facebook-Native-Ad.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 60%;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook Native ad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of Native Advertising on a News Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my walkthrough, news provider sites are often the best place to find native ads that offer the greatest value to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/native-advertising/News-Native-Ad.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 60%;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;News Native Ad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the more subtle nature of native ads, they are generally classified as a top-of-funnel activity, meant to produce awareness, and potentially stir up interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Who is Native Advertising For?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four primary pools of interest surrounding native advertising:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;base-ul&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;base-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publishers.&lt;/strong&gt; Publishers are interested because they will be showcasing these advertisements, whether they be digital or print format. Native ads also equate a growing source of ad revenue when many forms of display ads don’t seem to be quite as effective as they previously have been.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;base-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Businesses (You!).&lt;/strong&gt; Both small and large businesses are increasingly taking interest in using this newer form of advertising because consumers are beginning to associate display ads and pop-ups with “spam”. You may belong to any industry or vertical—an example being Capital One in the picture above.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;base-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing Agencies (Me!).&lt;/strong&gt; Digital service agencies are interested because this native advertising trend presents a new opportunity for us to provide the companies we serve with even greater value and variety in our offering. Our role is to write and strategize for the content, and arrange publishing for the companies that we serve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;base-li&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumers.&lt;/strong&gt; Everyday consumers and business customers are the last natural component in the who equation. They value native advertising because (when used properly) it is a means of delivering value to them while also producing awareness for the brand utilizing it. It is more responsible marketing if you will, none of that black-hat stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you good and confused? I was too, but thankfully graphics can just about always save the day for the more visual of us learners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How Native Advertising Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we know what a native ad looks like, we know who the stakeholders are, but it would be even better if we had an equation for how all of these stakeholders interact, wouldn’t it? Suffice it to say that it might be your lucky day (catch that rhyme?):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/native-advertising/newbrock-e1525814050434-768x476.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 60%;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;Native Ad diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You likely noticed that there are two different equations within this graphic. The difference in these two equations is generally de2018-07-11-Native-Advertisingtermined by whether or not the business in question has an in-house marketing department, or if they outsource their marketing to an agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, our friends at Capital One likely have their own marketing department, so they wouldn’t need a marketing agency’s help. However, your local business might not have the same resources or time to fulfill your own native ad work, so that’s where we can lend a helping hand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But back it up for a second, why should I be using native advertising anyways?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s investigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Native Advertising?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because native advertising works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that digital is mandatory today, and sometimes it simply takes a change of pace to add some flare to a tired marketing effort. Whether you’re on the publishing side, the business side, or the advertising side of the equation, you can create a balance between the traditional lines of display advertising and curating high quality, engaging content through native advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More traditional native advertising is a less-explored space than display advertising, but with consumers tiring of the “spam” and “brainwashing” of many display advertising campaigns, native is gathering momentum—fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Strengths of Native Advertising&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Telling Real Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For publishers surveyed in 2016 and 2017, one of the greatest challenges surrounding native advertising was convincing advertisers to tell real stories. Likely the result of advertisers having a somewhat difficult time transitioning to this unconventional style of advertising. The good news is that this category has declined 8% since 2016, meaning that advertisers are getting the feel for things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/native-advertising/Bigest-Challenge-Regarding-Native-Advertising.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 60%;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;Bigest-Challenge-Regarding-Native-Advertising&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Cross-Platform Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building a brand, it is very important to maintain a consistent story across all of the platforms that you are marketing and advertising, and the more platforms—the more exposure there is for a brand or a business. This activity is known as telling cross-platform stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native advertising might be one of the most effective ways to truly leverage a brands ability to tell a story due to the story-like nature of these ads. For example, it can be quite hard to tell a story in a 2 sentence Facebook post, but when you have an entire article, it makes it much easier to bring a branded story to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Native Advertising is (more) Effective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to some studies, click-through rates on native ads have been shown to reach nearly 4 times those of display ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/native-advertising/Native-Ad-Effectiveness.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 60%;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;Native-Ad-Effectiveness&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source: Native Advertising Institute&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may indicate that not only is native advertising a great complementary solution to digital advertising, but it may be able to replace current display advertising efforts to test for efficiency and improved advertising results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Adding Better Value to Local Business Offerings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growing native ad climate is the ideal time for marketing agencies and digital service providers to step-up and offer fulfilment to local businesses on this new realm of marketing. By outsourcing this content generation, local businesses don’t have to give up valuable time and resources in their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone can excel in exactly what they do best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://nativeadvertisinginstitute.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/inma_2017NativeAdvertising.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Native Advertising Trends in News Media&lt;/a&gt; for the full study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to try something new?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to Get Started with Native Advertising&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a local business and are ready to make take that next move, it’s pretty easy. You simply need to get in contact with your marketing agency (hopefully that’s me!) and see how we can get you involved in this promising space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By outsourcing this work, we can give you back valuable time in your day and our skilled team of content strategists is eager to fill those gaps for you. Contact us to learn more!&amp;lt;?p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Advertising" /><summary type="html">Native Advertising What is native advertising? Native advertising is an advertising tactic that is earning increased usage as either a complement to, or an alternative for, display advertising. It’s also a concept that plagues much of the digital marketing community with varying degrees of confusion. Luckily for you, I’ll get into the gritty details on this new supplementary and possibly replacement advertising service a little more below. What is Native Advertising? Native advertising is essentially a play on traditional display advertising (via banners and pop-ups), where advertisers have the opportunity to showcase their ads within the other content that publishing companies are already pushing out (be it Facebook or your local newspaper’s site). Advertisers contribute either a “sponsored”, a “promoted”, or a “branded” piece of content that generally still creates value for the reader, while also subtly alluding-to or referencing the brand that is paying to have it shown. This allows companies to advertise for themselves in a way that truly creates value for the consumer, while mitigating the frustrations that are often associated with pop-ups and banners. Need some examples? So did I. Examples of Native Advertising Depending on the platform it’s appearing on, native advertising can look and display differently. Lets cover a couple common examples you may see (or provide) on a daily basis. Example of Native Advertising on Facebook Facebook is one of the most popular websites in the world, so it makes sense that native advertising is a popular appearance on the platform. Example of Native Advertising on a News Website As mentioned in my walkthrough, news provider sites are often the best place to find native ads that offer the greatest value to consumers. Due to the more subtle nature of native ads, they are generally classified as a top-of-funnel activity, meant to produce awareness, and potentially stir up interest. Who is Native Advertising For? There are four primary pools of interest surrounding native advertising: Publishers. Publishers are interested because they will be showcasing these advertisements, whether they be digital or print format. Native ads also equate a growing source of ad revenue when many forms of display ads don’t seem to be quite as effective as they previously have been. Businesses (You!). Both small and large businesses are increasingly taking interest in using this newer form of advertising because consumers are beginning to associate display ads and pop-ups with “spam”. You may belong to any industry or vertical—an example being Capital One in the picture above. Marketing Agencies (Me!). Digital service agencies are interested because this native advertising trend presents a new opportunity for us to provide the companies we serve with even greater value and variety in our offering. Our role is to write and strategize for the content, and arrange publishing for the companies that we serve. Consumers. Everyday consumers and business customers are the last natural component in the who equation. They value native advertising because (when used properly) it is a means of delivering value to them while also producing awareness for the brand utilizing it. It is more responsible marketing if you will, none of that black-hat stuff. Are you good and confused? I was too, but thankfully graphics can just about always save the day for the more visual of us learners. How Native Advertising Works So we know what a native ad looks like, we know who the stakeholders are, but it would be even better if we had an equation for how all of these stakeholders interact, wouldn’t it? Suffice it to say that it might be your lucky day (catch that rhyme?): You likely noticed that there are two different equations within this graphic. The difference in these two equations is generally de2018-07-11-Native-Advertisingtermined by whether or not the business in question has an in-house marketing department, or if they outsource their marketing to an agency. For example, our friends at Capital One likely have their own marketing department, so they wouldn’t need a marketing agency’s help. However, your local business might not have the same resources or time to fulfill your own native ad work, so that’s where we can lend a helping hand! But back it up for a second, why should I be using native advertising anyways? Let’s investigate. Why Native Advertising? Because native advertising works. The reality is that digital is mandatory today, and sometimes it simply takes a change of pace to add some flare to a tired marketing effort. Whether you’re on the publishing side, the business side, or the advertising side of the equation, you can create a balance between the traditional lines of display advertising and curating high quality, engaging content through native advertising. More traditional native advertising is a less-explored space than display advertising, but with consumers tiring of the “spam” and “brainwashing” of many display advertising campaigns, native is gathering momentum—fast. The Strengths of Native Advertising 1. Telling Real Stories For publishers surveyed in 2016 and 2017, one of the greatest challenges surrounding native advertising was convincing advertisers to tell real stories. Likely the result of advertisers having a somewhat difficult time transitioning to this unconventional style of advertising. The good news is that this category has declined 8% since 2016, meaning that advertisers are getting the feel for things. 2. Cross-Platform Stories When building a brand, it is very important to maintain a consistent story across all of the platforms that you are marketing and advertising, and the more platforms—the more exposure there is for a brand or a business. This activity is known as telling cross-platform stories. Native advertising might be one of the most effective ways to truly leverage a brands ability to tell a story due to the story-like nature of these ads. For example, it can be quite hard to tell a story in a 2 sentence Facebook post, but when you have an entire article, it makes it much easier to bring a branded story to life. 3. Native Advertising is (more) Effective According to some studies, click-through rates on native ads have been shown to reach nearly 4 times those of display ads. Source: Native Advertising Institute This may indicate that not only is native advertising a great complementary solution to digital advertising, but it may be able to replace current display advertising efforts to test for efficiency and improved advertising results. 4. Adding Better Value to Local Business Offerings The growing native ad climate is the ideal time for marketing agencies and digital service providers to step-up and offer fulfilment to local businesses on this new realm of marketing. By outsourcing this content generation, local businesses don’t have to give up valuable time and resources in their day. Everyone can excel in exactly what they do best. Visit Native Advertising Trends in News Media for the full study. Ready to try something new? How to Get Started with Native Advertising If you are a local business and are ready to make take that next move, it’s pretty easy. You simply need to get in contact with your marketing agency (hopefully that’s me!) and see how we can get you involved in this promising space. By outsourcing this work, we can give you back valuable time in your day and our skilled team of content strategists is eager to fill those gaps for you. Contact us to learn more!&amp;lt;?p&amp;gt;</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Enhanced-SEO.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Complete WordPress SEO Plugin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/seo/CompleteWordPressSEOPluginMastery.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Complete WordPress SEO Plugin" /><published>2018-06-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-06-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/seo/CompleteWordPressSEOPluginMastery</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/seo/CompleteWordPressSEOPluginMastery.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Feature-Image-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WordPress SEO Plugin&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Complete WordPress SEO Plugin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEO is the key to conquering the internet, and as the digital climate becomes increasingly saturated, it is becoming more important than ever to make sure that you are making every effort to get seen on the web. One of the easiest ways to give your sites a little extra boost is by implementing the right WordPress plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Problem:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wait… I thought that finding the right SEO plugin was my problem?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re close. Everyone wants the one plugin that is going to single handedly cuddle their site up against that ever-desirable Google search bar. Although this result is possible, the reality is that the SEO market is becoming an increasingly competitive and saturated one. This context makes it more important than ever to have a better structured and optimized website with a search engine friendly hierarchy so that you can set yourself apart, and be ranked above your competition. Much to your dismay, that may involve a bit of a plugin stack.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Essential SEO Plugin Stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re building sites for clients, or your own business, mastering SEO will be the key to growing and sustaining a strong online presence.  Fortunately, we know how to get you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 7 critical pieces to the SEO puzzle. To start, you NEED an overall on-site SEO plugin to cover the basics, such as: meta tags, sitemaps, robots, etc. Then, there are an additional 6 complementary sections for plugins that will offer that competitive edge that you’re looking for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;On-site SEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Mobile Optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Broken Links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Image Optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Rich Snippet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is true that it’s a bit of a catch 22 when it comes to plugins and website speed, being that the shear volume of plugins being used will have an impact on the website speed. However, by using the right stack to build your SEO, the benefits will outweigh the harms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. On-site SEO Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An on-site SEO plugin will be the foundation of your infrastructure. For your convenience, we narrowed it down to only 2 contenders, Yoast SEO and All in One SEO Pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These 2 plugins have both been around for a decade already, and are still at the top of the food chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Yoast SEO&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free with Paid Premium Option&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through walk-throughs and advanced settings, &lt;a href=&quot;https://yoast.com/wordpress/plugins/seo/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yoast&lt;/a&gt; is the one stop shop for beginners and experts alike. Featuring sitemaps, title and meta descriptions, and the ability to connect Google Search Console, this plugin does everything to please users and search engine spiders alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With built in content and SEO analysis, Yoast can also insure that your content is always killer (in Google’s eyes as well as prospect’s eyes). By upgrading to premium, you also gain access to a local SEO extension which adds a local schema markup to your web pages.  Other premium features include video and news extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Yoast-Screenshot-768x553.png&quot; alt=&quot;Yoast SEO Plugin&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Most used SEO plugin on market with 5M+ active installs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Thousands of daily downloads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Effectively combines content and SEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Uses JSON_LD for local&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;5 star-rating across nearly 20,000 reviews on WordPress.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free with Paid Premium Option&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever get frustrated when you’re trying to look something up on your phone and it takes 3 full days to load? We all lead pretty busy lives, and just don’t have time for that nonsense.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/amp/&quot; target=&quot;_BLANK&quot;&gt;AMP for WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, you can insure that your prospects never give up hope as a result of a slow mobile site. By creating AMP content, which Google is now factoring into SEO rankings, this plugin caters to the needs of major AMP consumers such as Google Search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/All-in-One-Screenshot-768x272.png&quot; alt=&quot;SEO Screenshot&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;The ONLY free plugin to provide SEO Integration for e-Commerce sites, including WooCommerce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Over 3M active installs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;4.5 star-rating across 500+ reviews on WordPress.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoast SEO.&lt;/strong&gt; Industry experts and Vendastians all agree that Yoast is essentially the modern-day standard when it comes to WordPress SEO plugins. The free version will accommodate users of all levels of expertise and ensure all of your bases are covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Mobile Website Optimization Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SEO factor earned itself a priority seat due to the fact that Google is now favoring outlets that are running on AMP code. &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2018/01/using-page-speed-in-mobile-search.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google announced&lt;/a&gt; just last month, January 2018, that it would begin prioritizing pages with fast mobile loading speed in their search algorithm. What this means is that mobile optimization will now be a high ranking factor in every sites overall SEO performance on Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it more critical than ever to have your sites optimized for mobile. Considering that the majority of browsing these days is conducted from mobile devices, it just makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;AMP for WordPress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever get frustrated when you’re trying to look something up on your phone and it takes 3 full days to load? We all lead pretty busy lives, and just don’t have time for that nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/amp/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AMP for WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, you can insure that your prospects never give up hope as a result of a slow mobile site. By creating AMP content, which Google is now factoring into SEO rankings, this plugin caters to the needs of major AMP consumers such as Google Search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/AMP-for-WordPress-Screenshot-768x587.png&quot; alt=&quot;Design Screenshot&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Built by WordPress, not a third party, so compatibility is not a concern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Many 1 star reviews, and a 3.5 star overall rating on WordPress.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;200,000+ active installs (best in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;AMP for WP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Also free!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guys also spared no creativity in terms of naming themselves, but I guess that there’s no harm in getting to the point either…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/accelerated-mobile-pages/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AMP for WP&lt;/a&gt; is pretty straight-forward, and simply adds AMP functionality to your WordPress site to improve mobile site speed through search engines (like Google!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/AMP-for-WP-Screenshot-768x543.png&quot; alt=&quot;Price Center&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;100,000+ active installations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;4.5 star user rating on WordPress.org (best in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Yoast (and other SEO) plugin integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Mobile Optimization Winner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMP for WP&lt;/strong&gt; (the latter—these 2 are damn confusing). The reality is that both of these plugins are going to meet your mobile optimization needs, but it just feels like AMP for WordPress (the loser) has not put as much effort into customer satisfaction. Installs are declining and 1 star ratings on WordPress.org almost pair those of the 5 stars; which might be cause for some concern, ex:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/AMP-for-WordPress-Review.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tweet&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Broken Link Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links are kind of like family photos—sometimes they just go bad. Pages can be deleted, a site that you link to may vanish, or someone might move a post or page without updating others.  These actions can all cause broken links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is NOTHING worse than hitting a “404 Page not found” when you’re trying to find a new photographer for your family pictures.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By managing broken links on your site, you can mitigate user frustrations, questions of credibility, lost conversions, and damage to your SEO ranking. Yes, broken links factor quite heavily into your SEO ranking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Broken Link Checker&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broken Link Checker scans your posts, pages, comments, blogs, and custom fields to detect links that don’t work, images that may be missing, and link redirects. This parsing can take some time as it verifies each and every link tied to your site. Once completed, it will present you with a list of broken links so that you can manage redirects and prevent prospects and customers from losing interest or losing track of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Broken-Link-Checker-Screenshot-768x421.png&quot; alt=&quot;Broken Link Checker&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Has not been updated in 6 months…customer service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;500,000+ active installs (by far best in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;4 star rating across nearly 400 reviews on WordPress.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Offered in 30 languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Broken Link Winner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only one candidate, and only one winner. Use this plugin, it will save your customers and prospects a lot of headache, and it will help optimize your overall SEO.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Speed Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;age speed is a huge factor in search rankings because it a huge factor in user experience. Google recommends pages load in less than a half second, and that’s not always easy to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tie into the above AMP category, this element has actually never been more important with Google recently announcing that page speed is now a ranking factor for mobile searching (where most searches occur).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have offered up 2 site caching alternatives that will have a substantial impact on site load times, particularly with high volumes of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;WP Fastest Cache&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free, the best price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With most of the functionality automated, and active page statistics, the WP Fastest Cache plugin is very user friendly. It creates a static html file so that high quantities of traffic do not produce slow render times on your site, and offers numerous options for managing cached files. It also comes with minify html and css options so that users can decrease the size of pages and css files.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/WP-Fastest-Cache-Screenshot-2-768x595.png&quot; alt=&quot;WP Fastest Cache Optin&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Does not yet support WordPress Multisite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;5 star rating and over 500,000 active installations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Offered in 17 languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;W3 Total Cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Price: Free, always.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W3 Total Cache improves SEO and user experience by reducing dowload times and increasing performance. W3 comes with a host of caching options, minification features, as well as various security features. It also offers improved server performance to help weather those high traffic periods.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/W3-Total-Cache-Screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;W3 Total Cache&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Only 9 out of 108 issues resolved in the past 2 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;4.5 star rating and over 1 million active installs (best in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Used by many large companies such as AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Speed Winner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually a really tough one. I am going to crown W3 Total Cache as the victor for now due to the sheer volume of active users and the number of industry experts that swear by it. However, WP Fastest Cache is an excellent caching plugin, and is growing in popularity and downloads, so it would also make for a great alternative should you choose it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. Security Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is a factor that owns varying degrees of concern. If you are a financial institution or a related field of business, security will likely hold a much greater precedence in your site infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary impact of a security plugin for other business demographics is in regards to an SSL certificate (https). This certificate helps your site maintain rank on search providers and is rumoured to become a requirement for google sites in the near future. An SSL certificate can also directly translate to growth in rank, while also encrypting user data – an essential component on many websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, who wants to be hacked by some sneaky black hat spammer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Wordfence Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free with Premium Option&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/wordfence/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wordfence Security&lt;/a&gt; was built for the specific application of WordPress sites. It includes an endpoint firewall and malware scanner, as well as a Threat Defence Feed that insures that Wordfence is always up to date with the newest firewall rules, malware signatures, and malicious IP addresses it needs to keep your site safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Wordfence-Screenshot-768x576.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wordfence&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;2M+ active installs (best in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;5 star rating across over 3000 reviews on WordPress.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;User friendly feeds to monitor performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Security Winner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to keep it simple on this one being that Wordfence Security is all around best in class. This plugin is a favorite by industry experts worldwide, so it will surely meet your firewall and malware needs in the free version—with the option to pay for premium as you grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;6. Image Optimization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The images that you utilize on your site build can have a huge impact on user experience as well as click and conversion rates. However, it is critical that you don’t forget to use an image optimization plugin to reduce image sizes (often up to 50%), and therefore page sizes, to boost your SEO rankings by greatly increasing page speed and user-friendliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of compressors, but really only a couple in the runnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Smush Image Compression and Optimization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free with Pro Option&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smush, seems like a fitting name right? This plugin does the bulk of the heavy lifting for you, so you really don’t need to stress about a steep learning curve. Smush automatically cuts the size of all of the images on your site to provide speed and quality. It also now allows for image resizing and is compatible with numerous other plugins on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Smush-Screenshot-768x463.png&quot; alt=&quot;Smush&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;5 star rating and over 1 million active installs (best in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Huge benefits for mobile speeds/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Highest performance reserved for paying customers only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Short Pixel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free with Paid Premium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short Pixel is on this list as a result of its cheaper premium option in comparison to the other image optimizers on the market. This plugin will accomplish relatively the same as Smush, but nearly all of these image optimization plugins are drastically limited in the free versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, if you find yourself growing, and in need of something more than what these free versions can offer, Short Pixel has one off the most affordable paid rates on the market, and will still reach upwards of 60% optimization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Short-Pixel-Screenshot-768x350.png&quot; alt=&quot;Short Pixel&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;They have resolved every single issue that has been reported to WordPress.org in the past 2 months (can somebody say customer service?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;4.5 star rating across nearly 300 reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Also offers huge benefits for mobile site speeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;One click bulk optimization (major time saver)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Image Optimization Winner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being that I recognized each of these plugins for different benefits, they are both winners in their own light. Smush is a near unanimous favorite for basic free image optimization, and ShortPixel is a great alternative if you are ready to take that first step into the realm of “paid plugins,” but don’t necessarily want to invest the capital that Smush or many others require.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;7. Rich Snippet Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is a Rich Snippet?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich snippets are the fields that spice up your search result listing. You know those sites that have pictures and external ratings linked into their descriptions? There is less sorcery involved than you may have thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s special about this plugin is that you don’t have to write any code what-so-ever (and if your coding is anything like mine, this is a major blessing). Rich Snippet plugins present fields that you fill in, and the plugin automatically generates the code and tags for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many website developers might not consider rich snippets an important tool in terms of SEO, but I’ll tell you why this interaction is important. Although rich snippets do not directly help you rank, they do provide increased visual appeal to your SERP result as you approach that first page of google. This visual appeal will likely increase your click through rate (CTR) which will then cause you to rank higher in terms of SEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;All In One Schema Rich Snippets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price: Free&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevator Pitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to add review, event, product, recipe, video, article, or other schemas to your site snippet?  All In One Schema Rich Snippets makes it possible in a highly user-friendly format so that you can make your site more interactive and improve your click through rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Rich-Snippet-Screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rich Snippetl&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;70,000+ active installs (by far best in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;4.5 star rating across 100+ reviews on WordPress.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Helps Facebook display proper information when users share your links on Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;The Rich Snippet Winner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;I know, I did it again…to date, All in One Schema Rich Snippets has more or less monopolized the market, and is your best choice if you want to master all of the categories of SEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;on your WordPress build.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seven&lt;/strong&gt; is the number of plugins you are going to need to have a world class SEO optimized site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Yoast SEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;AMP for WP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Broken Link Checker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;W3 Total Cache&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Wordfence Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Smush or ShortPixel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;All In One Schema Rich Snippets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one is the page number of Google results that you will likely find yourself on the keywords that matter most if you leverage this plugin combination.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">The Complete WordPress SEO Plugin SEO is the key to conquering the internet, and as the digital climate becomes increasingly saturated, it is becoming more important than ever to make sure that you are making every effort to get seen on the web. One of the easiest ways to give your sites a little extra boost is by implementing the right WordPress plugins.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Enhanced-SEO.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Improving Local Search Rankings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/listings/Improve-Local-Search-Aggregators.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Improving Local Search Rankings" /><published>2018-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/listings/Improve-Local-Search-Aggregators</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/listings/Improve-Local-Search-Aggregators.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/data-aggregatorsBlog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Local Search Data Aggregators&quot; class=&quot;img-responstive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Improving Local Search Rankings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data aggregators run the world. The world of local search, any way. Data aggregators supply information to major search engines like Google, which means that having good business listing info on data aggregators can help it get right on Google. These aggregators have built massive business databases from valuable listing sources like yellow page directories, phone directories, utility records, and various online information providers. They’ve got an unbelievable amount of business data that search engines look to when finding local listing information for businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four major data providers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.factual.com/&quot; title=&quot;Data Aggregators: Factual&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Factual&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acxiom.com/&quot; title=&quot;Data Aggregators: Acxiom&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Acxiom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infogroup.com/&quot; title=&quot;Data Aggregators: Infogroup&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Infogroup&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neustarlocaleze.biz/&quot; title=&quot;Data Aggregators: Localeze&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Localeze&lt;/a&gt;. Their databases contain business information that search engines seek out to display for consumers. This information is the basis of where many online citations come from. What exactly is a citation, you ask? Citations are when a business is mentioned somewhere online, and the more citations a business has generated, the more likely their business is to &lt;a href=&quot;http://searchengineland.com/local-seo-rank-local-business-218906&quot; title=&quot;Local SEO: How To Rank Your Local Business&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;appear higher in search rankings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major data aggregators provide information that help businesses get found correctly on online resources such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bing Local&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yahoo Local&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple/Siri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yellow Pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These online resources are only a few of the sources that receive data from the data aggregators. Obviously sites like Google Maps, Facebook and Yellow Pages are crucial places to be listed for businesses that want to be found online. Businesses need to get their information correct with these data providers, or they risk not being found by potential consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every business wants online visibility! Do you want to master SEO with all of the major data aggregators, and generate and as many business citations as possible? I thought so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is a citation?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitespark.ca/blog/post/13-what-is-a-citation&quot; title=&quot;What is a Local Citation&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;citation is simply anytime a business is mentioned somewhere online&lt;/a&gt;. Many people believe that citations are links to websites, but this isn’t necessarily true. Although a citation can be linked, they don’t have to contain a link to be considered a citation. To break it down further, let’s look at how citations can appear online:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company name (alone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone number (alone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company name and phone number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company name, phone number and address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company name, phone number, address and link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though any of these combinations is considered a citation, a citation is not considered to be complete unless it contains the company name, address and phone number (NAP). Businesses who have their NAP data correct with the major data providers have a better chance of seeing their correct information appearing all across the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citations can appear in a structured or unstructured manner, here’s how you can distinguish the difference between the two:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A structured citation is the most common type of citation, and usually the most detailed when consumers are looking for business information. People see structured business citations on business listing sites like Yellowpages, Yelp or TripAdvisor. In most cases, these citations contain the NAP for a business, something consumers are looking for in local search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An unstructured citation can be found on random websites, blogs, event listings, job posting sites, government records or social media mentions. These are unstructured because they could be as simple as a company mention. Usually these citations don’t include a business’s NAP data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how a citation appears, it has influence on the local search ranking in some way for a particular business. Data aggregators play an important role in getting a business listed or found on many major websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The importance of building citations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citations have a major influence on &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/local-search-ranking-factors&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;2017 Local Search Ranking Factors&quot;&gt;local search rankings&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, the more times a business is mentioned online, the better chance their business has to rank near the top of local search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://searchengineland.com/everything-need-know-pigeon-algorithm-211771&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;
Everything You Need To Know About Google’s Local Algorithm, Pigeon&quot;&gt;Google’s search ranking algorithm&lt;/a&gt; has many moving parts, which means that citation building isn’t the only thing a business has to do in order to rank on search engines. Online reviews, mobile compatibility, domain authority and keyword density are just a few other factors that influence local search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean that citations don’t play an important role in &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/business/answer/7091?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Improve your local ranking on Google&quot;&gt;local search ranking&lt;/a&gt;, though. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidmihm.com/local-search-ranking-factors.shtml&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Ranking Factors&quot;&gt;David Mihm’s local search study&lt;/a&gt; suggest that citation related factors are very important: they make up 25% of the top twenty factors the influence local search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;So what do data aggregators do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data aggregators provide a lot of the data to search engines when conducting a local search. The aggregators own the space known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/learn/local/local-search-data-us&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;The U.S. Local Search Ecosystem&quot;&gt;local search ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;, a place where local searches get all of their data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/local-search-ecosystem.png&quot; alt=&quot;The U.S. Local Search Ecosystem&quot; class=&quot;img-responstive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you see the four major data aggregators: Infogroup, Acxiom, Localeze, and Factual. As you can see, many major directories and listings sites rely on these data providers for their information. Like we mentioned earlier, the data aggregators are the foundation of what builds structured citations on major sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the picture might seem like a lot to comprehend, the underlying message that you should take away from this is really simple: get business data right with the major data aggregators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incorrect data on any of these aggregators could mean that a business’s information online is extremely inconsistent or down right wrong on many major listings sites and directories. Inconsistent information hurts SEO, so be sure to have your business correctly listed with all the major players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does inconsistency hurt search engine ranking, but it hurts a business. Consumers don’t trust businesses with inconsistent information online—73% of &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchenginewatch.com/sew/study/2338839/73-lose-trust-in-brands-due-to-inaccurate-local-business-listings-survey&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Local Business Listings Survey&quot;&gt;consumers lose trust in brands due to inaccurate local business listings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business citations rely on the power of data aggregators! We see that data aggregators have a major influence on the amount of reputable sources that a business is cited on because they automatically input business data into various sources for a business. This means not having to manually plug in information into each and every business-relevant site on the worldwide web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get it right!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no secret that we are keeping from you, or a fancy trick to increasing online citations. It’s as simple as getting it right with the major data aggregators. Local search is a major deal for businesses, especially for small businesses. A company could potentially force themselves into bankruptcy if their online visibility is non-existent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumers rely on the internet and search engines to interact with local businesses. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/articles/how-advertisers-can-extend-their-relevance-with-search.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;How Advertisers Can Extend Their Relevance With Search&quot;&gt;According to Google&lt;/a&gt;, “four in five consumers use search engines to find products, services or experiences nearby.” These are searches for anything, from the best pizza in town to the fastest hair salon. Local search is what drives consumers to a business’s front door, and ultimately drives top-line revenue for local business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that your business gets it right, and isn’t missing from vital local search results. Start using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_aggregation&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Deffinition of Data aggregation&quot;&gt;data aggregator&lt;/a&gt;: it’s the first step in building accurate online citations and mastering local SEO.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Listings" /><summary type="html">Improving Local Search Rankings Data aggregators run the world. The world of local search, any way. Data aggregators supply information to major search engines like Google, which means that having good business listing info on data aggregators can help it get right on Google. These aggregators have built massive business databases from valuable listing sources like yellow page directories, phone directories, utility records, and various online information providers. They’ve got an unbelievable amount of business data that search engines look to when finding local listing information for businesses.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Listing_Sync_Pro_High_Res.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Engage Your Audience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/social/EngageYouAudience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Engage Your Audience" /><published>2018-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/social/EngageYouAudience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/social/EngageYouAudience.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/engage-social-mediaBlog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Engage Your Audience&quot; class=&quot;img-responstive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Engage Your Audience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your social media falling flat? Don’t sweat it; many hours have gone into perfecting the use of this not-so-secret weapon. Facebook, Google+, Twitter, Pinterest, and Instagram strategies are outlined in detail below. Once you understand how they all work and which will suit your business best, learn how to handle them and other factors such as SEO, reviews, and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Facebook, Google+, &amp;amp; Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What works:&lt;/strong&gt; Images, videos, calls to action, industry-related content, general share-worthy content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What doesn’t work:&lt;/strong&gt; Lengthy content, bland content, poor business/related/share-worthy balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Videos and images are best used to catch the eye of social media readers, though video works a little better to hold the reader’s attention. Whether it’s redirecting consumers to your website or online store, or getting them to stop and look at an interesting piece of content titled by your business, images and videos are your anchor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three best ways to get traction from your readers are to:&lt;p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Get them to go straight to your website or store&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Get them to like/follow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;and/or get them to share your content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say three people see your business posts about that 2 for 1 sale. These posts are not likely to be shared, so those same three people will see all your posts, and that’s it. Once people start liking and sharing your posts, you’ll start to see new eyes on your page. This is where industry related/general share-worthy content comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a physical therapist, for example, get your readers excited to see and share those workout tips and you’ll have a better chance that someone who needs physical therapy will come across them. Having a good mix of these types of posts is extremely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gained the attention of your readers with a photo or video, a call to action is a great way to guide them to their next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Do you like these home renovation ideas? Let’s get started with yours!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen in this above example, calls to action can be used for almost every type of post. Tell your reader to check out your website for a business related post, or tell them to read the article or video you’re sharing. Though industry-related or share-worthy content may not lead your reader straight to your website, the posts are more likely to gain likes and shares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Packaged in with the importance of shared content is the name of your business. Every time your post is shared, someone new has the chance to see you. That’s brand-recognition, baby! When the time comes for that person to need a lawyer, they’ll remember the interesting law posts you shared and seek out the name they remember seeing or hearing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, lengthy content, bland posts, and a poor balance of business/industry/shareable don’t work well on these media channels. Lengthy content is an especially bad choice for Twitter’s 140 character count limit. As for Facebook and Google+, people just don’t have the attention spans to read posts that are more than a couple of lines long. Keep them short and concise! Don’t post bland, filler content like, “Happy Friday!” unless people have a reason to share it. “Happy Friday, here’s a hilarious cat meme” can improve brand recognition, but only if shared- use humor to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find your balance between business and shareable content. Too much boring business related posts and calls to action can lead to a stagnant viewer count, while too many share-worthy posts may lead to your readers not knowing what your business does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pinterest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What works:&lt;/strong&gt; Images, videos, industry related content, general share-worthy content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What doesn’t work:&lt;/strong&gt; Lengthy content, bland content, and it may not suit your vertical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinterest, like Instagram below, is all about the pictures. If you’ve ever been on Pinterest, you know that it’s a very visual sight to behold. The hook of Pinterest is that people are looking for ideas. This will work best for you if your business provides ideas or the means with which to make ideas happen. A hardware store can benefit from Pinterest because you may share tree-house building ideas with your store’s name attached- don’t forget about brand recognition. Once people get the ideas from you, they’ll come into your store to buy the tools they need for the job! The best use of Pinterest includes non-business related content. Show people ideas that may lead them to your business, but don’t try to sell them right then and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Pinterest may not suit your vertical, and it definitely won’t prosper with too much emphasis on text. Many verticals such as plumbing just don’t have many corresponding ideas given the nature of the job. In this case, Pinterest can only be used for shareable content and brand recognition. The text attached to Pinterest posts is often ignored, so any applicable text should go into an infographic displayed as an image. That isn’t to say that you shouldn’t use any text. A small headline or message will suffice here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Instagram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What works:&lt;/strong&gt; Images, projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What doesn’t work:&lt;/strong&gt; Mostly everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram is a strange beast. The entire point of this medium is to compel readers to follow you and talk about what you offer. This works best for verticals like restaurants because your customers can post images of your food for their friends to see. This also works great for verticals like home improvement. In this vertical, your business can post project and progress images of what you’ve been working on. Seeing these images and sharing them can work well to compel the reader to seek you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram posts can’t include links, so just like Pinterest, the aim here is brand recognition. Can you consistently post interesting enough images for your readers to stay interested? Not every business can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Reviews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered the main social media channels, let’s discuss other ways they can be used. Facebook, Google+, and other media channels support reviews. Aside from the engagement from posts, reviews can make or break a business. You may be thinking “I can’t control what people rate my business”, and you’d be right. However, you can control how you respond to people. You can turn around even the angriest rater by replying to their review in a quick and professional manner. See our other articles to learn about the importance of reviews!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Social Listening&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forbes discusses social listening as finding where your audience is discussing topics related to your brand. People are talking about cars somewhere, and these are great topics for your dealership. The short and sweet of this is that you need to be researching your competitors and your peers. What are people talking about, liking, and sharing, and how can you get in on it? You’ll want to shape your social media strategies around what’s getting the best traction everywhere else. Get researching!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;SEO&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This likely isn’t the first time you’ve read about the importance of SEO, and it definitely won’t be your last. When you search your business’s name or keywords related to your work, how high on the results page does it appear? The more you and your readers are mentioning your name and other keywords in relation to your business, the better your SEO results will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Measure Success&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, take a step back and look at what you’re doing. Naturally, you’ll want to look for what’s working and what isn’t. Whether you’re counting likes and shares by hand or using Google Analytics to track the information for you, understanding your trends may just be the most important part of the process, so what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Social" /><summary type="html">Engage Your Audience Is your social media falling flat? Don’t sweat it; many hours have gone into perfecting the use of this not-so-secret weapon. Facebook, Google+, Twitter, Pinterest, and Instagram strategies are outlined in detail below. Once you understand how they all work and which will suit your business best, learn how to handle them and other factors such as SEO, reviews, and more!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Social_Marketing_High_Res.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Social Media Monitoring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/social/Social-Media-Monitoring.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Media Monitoring" /><published>2018-02-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-02-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/social/Social-Media-Monitoring</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/social/Social-Media-Monitoring.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/2017-09-15_social-media-monitoring_fi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Social Media Monitoring&quot; class=&quot;img-responstive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Social Media Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been at a party and caught a person or a group glancing at you while whispering covertly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s up with that? Is your fly open? Does someone have a crush on you? Does someone want to throw a drink in your face?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;You’d want to know, wouldn’t you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online universe is a lot like that party; It’s a system of digital communities in which people are gathering and discussing a wide variety of topics, including YOU. In your personal life, you may or may not care to find out what they’re saying, but in business, it’s essential to your survival that you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the party, you may never get the answers you seek without shaking someone down. However, online, you can use social media monitoring to track mentions of your brand, competitors, product and any other keywords that are applicable to your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitoring your social media channels is about more than just listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information you accumulate can help you make major decisions about your marketing strategy, the products and services you offer and how people regard your brand. Plus, it can help you identify leads, build relationships, stay on top of trends, learn about your competitors, protect your brand and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This post is outlining organic social media monitoring tips, as opposed to paid social campaigns. Organic social media is more geared toward building brand awareness and connecting with your target audience. Paid social is typically centered around driving targeted actions like content downloads, webinar or appointment signups, and other specific goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s more on why it’s so important that you monitor what people are saying about your business online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Should You Use Social Media Monitoring?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To gauge social sentiment:
&lt;p&gt;What do you know about your brand’s reputation? You can get a feel by reading your reviews and speaking with customers, but you’d be missing a wealth of more informal brand or product mentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, you need to be there to respond! In a recent survey, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sproutsocial.com/insights/data/q2-2016/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Survey by Sprout Social&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprout Social&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found that 89% of social messages go ignored. That’s a problem—and an even bigger missed opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People use social media to discuss the topics they care about within the communities they choose. That’s where you need to listen to truly discover how people regard your business, the issues they’re having, and the things they love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To find leads &amp;amp; build relationships:
    &lt;p&gt;Are people searching for your products and services? You’ve seen those calls on Facebook for recommendations, or the plaintive cries for help on Twitter: “I want pizza!” When you monitor your brand’s keywords or phrases, you can jump in and answer these requests (Just mention your current Monday 2 for 1 pizza deal!). NOT selling anything can be really effective too. Be a part of the conversations that are happening online about your industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To stay on top of trends:
&lt;p&gt;When you’re closely monitoring discussions in your niche, you may be able to catch new and evolving trends as they emerge. For example, when Instagram launched its “Stories” product, Snapchat growth took a major hit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/02/slowchat/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Snapchat Growth reviews&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rowth slowed by 82%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). In response to news like this, you may decide to alter your marketing strategy to be one of the first to dive into a new social channel or try a new tactic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/snapchat-stat.png&quot; alt=&quot;Snap Inc.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/02/slowchat/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Info Source Techcrunch&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Techcrunch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why is this important?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In an over-saturated market, doing the same thing as everyone else can get you lost in the crowd. Finding ways to stand out will help you get noticed and stay relevant in your industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To perform competitor research:
&lt;p&gt;Has your competition launched a product similar to what you offer, but at a lower price or with a few more bells and whistles? Did they just launch a marketing strategy that your customers are loving? Did they just screw up royally using a tactic you’ve been considering? Keeping your finger on the social pulse will alert you about these types of scenarios and unforeseen issues that may have huge repercussions for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To protect your brand:
&lt;p&gt;Building your brand’s reputation takes a lot of time and effort, but it can all be lost in seconds.Monitoring your social channels allows you to identify any issues customers have and jump on solutions before they blow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stuff happens. It’s inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s how you respond and how quickly you respond that matters. In fact, we’ve found that if a business resolves its issue quickly and efficiently, 95% of unhappy customers return to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening, identifying the issue and showing your customers you care and are taking steps to resolve the issue is what can turn them from a brand killer into a champion for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What to Do With Your Social Media Monitoring Insights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So once you’re set up with the tools you need for monitoring, tracking, measuring and analysis, what do you do with the information? This is the key moment where you determine how to act on the knowledge you’ve received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Shift Social Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your strategy working? Are you truly getting traction on your primary social channels? You may discover that it’s time to re-evaluate the resources and effort you put into certain channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, maybe you discover that your people are super engaged in Quora. Devoting more time and resources there would be worth pursuing, even if it’s at the expense of another social channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results from monitoring your competitors on social media could also yield some interesting insights as well. You may find that a new video tactic has people in your area or industry buzzing about a close competitor. Why let them go unchallenged?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Work on Developing Relationships With Leads &amp;amp; Influencers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can jump into conversations and authentically solve problems for people, do it! This tactic can be especially relevant when it comes to people’s frustrations with your competitor’s products or services. When you do this, it’s essential that you come from a really genuine place and offer tips or advice geared around helping people. People don’t want to be spammed, and sensitive topics like plastic surgery should be off-limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in many industries you should feel free to have real conversations with people around the topics they care about (which also happen to be topics YOU care about as a business owner!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spotting and reaching out to influencers in your industry as outlined in this post (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salesforce.com/ca/blog/2016/06/establish-relationships-with-influencers.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Review by Salesforce&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salesforce&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) can have an amazing amplification effect for your brand as well. People look to influencers to help them make purchasing decisions all the time, and if you can develop strong relationships with key influencers you can expect better results for much less work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/images/Blog/salesforce-sales-768x919.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Salesforce&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Image Source: Salesforce&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Develop New Products/Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to the needs of your target audience is a smart way to refine your solutions and develop new ones. If enough people are saying they hate a product, or wish they could tweak it, it’s probably worth looking into what the issue is and try to determine what could make that product better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Natalia Chrzanowska of (&lt;a href=&quot;https://brand24.com/blog/12-powerful-ways-social-listening-help-business/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Brand24 Notes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) notes that GoPro did exactly that when they introduced their new camera – GoPro Hero4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We analyzed the social media discussions regarding both releases – Hero3+ and Hero4. The insights gathered during the Hero3+ premiere included lots of suggestions for features that could improve customer experience, which then appeared later on in the succeeding model&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;footer&gt; – GoPro Hero4.&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, if your customers LOVE one of your products, there may be an opportunity to develop similar or complimentary products or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can then turn around and apply all this awesome feedback as testimonials for new campaigns. Think ad campaigns, email campaigns, social campaigns and beyond!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Update Customer Service Policy/Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media has led to a major shift in how customer service is carried out by many companies. People want instant answers, and are less likely to put up with call centers. Many won’t even pick up the phone when they have a problem; They’ll just tweet about it! According to a new report from Conversocial, 54% of customers prefer customer service via social media and SMS. The upcoming generation of millennials will only amplify this trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are sticking to their favorite social media platforms to air out their complaints, and you need to know if this is happening in your industry (and be ready for it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jay Baer’s book Hug Your Haters, author and consultant Dave Kerpen notes that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;“If a customer calls you on the phone to complain, surely you wouldn’t hang up on them. And not responding in social media is akin to hanging up on them, only worse, because there are actually other people watching and listening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting complains hang out there unanswered is not acceptable to current and potential customers, and it shouldn’t be to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4 Easy Wins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve thrown a lot of information you’re way. It’s easy to get overwhelmed and put off testing these strategies for yourself. To help you get started, here are a few easy action items for you to try out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;basic-ul&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Jot down 3 of your top goals that you’re hoping monitoring your social channels will help you with. (example: Find out if people are liking the new kombucha flavor we just released).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Contact us to get set up with the social media monitoring tools you need. Poke around and see what value you can get out of the tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Enter a few of your brand’s keywords and see what data the tools come up with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Look through the initial results. Make a list of 3 things you learned and whether you should
 discuss with your team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most businesses are aware that they should monitor social media for mentions related to their brand, products, services, competitors and industry. You might actually be doing so already. But do you have a plan in place to analyze, respond and integrate results into your business’s ongoing strategy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t, you might be missing some golden opportunities…or you could get a martini in your face!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Social" /><summary type="html">Social Media Monitoring Have you ever been at a party and caught a person or a group glancing at you while whispering covertly? What’s up with that? Is your fly open? Does someone have a crush on you? Does someone want to throw a drink in your face? You’d want to know, wouldn’t you?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Social_Marketing_High_Res.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Online Presence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/tips%20&%20tricks/Online-Presence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online Presence" /><published>2018-02-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-02-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/tips%20&amp;%20tricks/Online-Presence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/tips%20&amp;%20tricks/Online-Presence.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/online-presence.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Online Presence&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Online Presence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is your online presence?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything online that reflects you and/or your business. Your online presence is more than just about your business it is also about you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are you presenting your self and your business online?
Through your companies website, social media accounts,  articles &amp;amp; citations about your business and you; post and tweets, and your search engine and directory listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WOW! I know. If you or your business can be found somewhere online that is your online presence. You want to make sure that you are representing your company the best you can online through your personal appearance to your business appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to Build our business online presence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/3-tips-for-building-your-online-presence.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Building you Online Presence&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaffeinated Kodemonkey offers a Reputation Management tool that monitors what is being said about you online and lets you know so that you can fix, rebuttal or thank the poster of the comment or article. Part of your online presence is making sure that anything said about you or your company is accurate falsification can hurt your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great blog is the one I read from &lt;a href=&quot;https://brandyourself.com&quot; title=&quot;How to BrandYourSelf&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BrandYourself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a hreff=&quot;https://brandyourself.com/blog/guide/how-to-clean-up-facebook-accounts/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Clean up Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How To Clean Up Facebook Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. They explain why this is important and what to look for when cleaning up y our account. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-7&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&quot;basic-ul&quot;&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Derogatory Language&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Unprofessional Work or School Behavior&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Violence or Bullying&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;rresponsible Drinking or Drug Use&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Criminal Behavior&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Sexually Explicit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Unprofessional Communication Style&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-5&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brandyourself.com&quot; title=&quot;BrandYourSelf&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/brand-yourself-348x348.jpg&quot; allt=&quot;BrandYourslf&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would recommend you give the &lt;a href=&quot;https://brandyourself.com&quot; title=&quot;How to BrandYourSelf&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BrandYourself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tips &amp; Tricks" /><summary type="html">Online Presence What is your online presence? Anything online that reflects you and/or your business. Your online presence is more than just about your business it is also about you. How are you presenting your self and your business online? Through your companies website, social media accounts, articles &amp;amp; citations about your business and you; post and tweets, and your search engine and directory listings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google My Business</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/tips%20&%20tricks/Googl-My-Business.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google My Business" /><published>2018-02-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/tips%20&amp;%20tricks/Googl-My-Business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/tips%20&amp;%20tricks/Googl-My-Business.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/google-my-business-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google My Business&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Google My Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a free to Claim our GMB lising. Once you do so you will be able to manage your presence on Google’s search engine. When someone searches for your business on Google, your NAP information - Name, Adress, Phone gets pulled from your Google My Business listing and will populate in the results on the right of the search page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Claiming your GMB Listing helps drive traffic to your business website and storefront. You will be build a better presence in the search results and gaining trust with customers. Business that claim their GMB listing are rated higher than business that have not yet claimed their listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The added bonus of Google is that once you have a gmail email you have access to a plethora of Google products that are free. GMB is just one of them, however you will have access to Google Analytics, Adwords, Webmaster Tools, etc. I will not touch on them in this post, however I may pick them up in future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to claim your GMB Listing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Business-Listing-FB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Claim GMB Listing&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you will need a gmail email. If you do not have one you can get one here try to use your business name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a gmail account you can claim your GMB Listing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;basic-ul&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Sign in to your Google Account or create an account for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;www.google.com&quot; title=&quot;Google Homepage&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;. Type in your business name and city and click search. For this example, we are using a fiction business called &quot;Moe's Dog Grooming&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;On the right had side, you will see the Search options. Click on &quot;Maps&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Next you will see a map of your location region, with your business listed on the left hand side of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Click on your business name, and a location box will appear on the Map (see below example)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Click on the &quot;More info&quot; in your location box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats it now have fun and don't forget to make Google Posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having issue or need to chat with our support team you can  email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@kaffeinatedkodemonkey.com?subject=GMB-Post&quot; title=&quot;GMB Support&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Kodemokey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
Or start a conversation in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tips &amp; Tricks" /><summary type="html">Google My Business It’s a free to Claim our GMB lising. Once you do so you will be able to manage your presence on Google’s search engine. When someone searches for your business on Google, your NAP information - Name, Adress, Phone gets pulled from your Google My Business listing and will populate in the results on the right of the search page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Critical Data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/listings/Critical-Data.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Critical Data" /><published>2018-02-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-02-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/listings/Critical-Data</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/listings/Critical-Data.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/nap-data-critical-listings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Critical Data&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Critical Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to rank well in local search, you need consistent NAP data, website, hours, and more across all major listing
directories. This is essential for search engines to validate you as a credible local business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more accurate and consistent data there is about your business across the web, the more search engines will trust the validity of the business. And the more the search engines trust the business, the higher they will rank in local SERPs (Search Engine Results Page).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Moz in their 2017 Local Search Ranking Factors survey, 13% of professionals list citation signals as the most important element in Local Pack Ranking factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/pie-chart.png&quot; alt=&quot;Local Pack/Finder Ranking Factors&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What’s in an online business listing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information contained in business listings can vary across verticals and directories—but some key pieces of information hold true across them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;nap&lt;/span&gt; Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most crucial data held in a business listing is the NAP data—name, address, and phone number information. NAP data is critical for the online visibility of any business, and every listing source contains this information for the businesses listed. Having correct NAP data ensures that not only will consumers find your business online, but that consumers will also have accurate, up-to-date information on how to contact you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;nap&lt;/span&gt; data is also important for search engines like Google to display your business in geo-targeted searches. If someone is searching “good seafood” in the Boston area, the local Boston seafood places with correct NAP data will appear. Of course Google gives search ranking priority to business with correct &lt;span class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;nap&lt;/span&gt; data—how else are they supposed to tell where you are, what you do, and if you’re even a legitimate business at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumers are looking for your business! What exactly are they looking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-ul&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;53% of mobile searchers are looking for directions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;50% are looking for business addresses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://think.storage.googleapis.com/docs/how-advertisers-can-extend-their-relevance-with-search_research-studies.pdf&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Download PDF: Think with Google&quot;&gt;Think with Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the importance of accurate NAP data, our data shows that many businesses are failing even at this basic step into the world of listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-ul&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;86% of businesses have either missing or incorrect company name information listed across all listings sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;72% of businesses have either missing or incorrect address information listed across all listings sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;71% of businesses have either missing or incorrect phone number information listed across all listings sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data taken from the 140,000+ local businesses in our system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Screen-Shot-2017-08-23-at-8.38.10-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Graph&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hours of Operation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important details about your business to include besides NAP data is the hours of operation. When a consumer is searching for their business (or their goods/services), they have a high purchase intent, and are likely searching for an immediate need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consumer will likely a visit a business after the business is shown as “open” on their Google search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/hours-of-operation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Maps&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your business has no hours listed, the consumer would have to go out of their way to find out whether you’re open or closed from their website, or a phone call. Or, worse yet, they drive to visit your business and find that you’re closed! Now they’re not only inconvenienced by not knowing your business hours, but they’re also upset for wasting their time. Let the negative reviews commence!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your competitor has their business hours listed, they’ll likely capture that consumer. People just want their needs fulfilled—they’d be happy to spend their money at a business that has their hours correctly listed if they were coming in-store to make the purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;73% of purchases that result from mobile searches happen within the same day, and most (63%) within a few hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;76% of consumers report that they expected hours of operation information when conducting a search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Over 60% of consumers find that knowing the business hours helps them make their purchase decision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neustarlocaleze.biz/docs/comScoreNeustar-Localeze2015TrendsinLocalSearch.pdf?mkt_tok=3RkMMJWWfF9wsRoku6TIce%2FhmjTEU5z16ukpXaKxg5Z41El3fuXBP2XqjvpVQcNmN73LRw8FHZNpywVWM8TIKNARt9B5LwzkAG8%3D&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Localeze&quot;&gt;Localeze, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumers are often looking to make purchases the same day that they’re searching, so make sure they know your store is open when they go looking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does your business have a central “hub” of information to direct users to online? Throw that website link into your business listings. Consumers will often travel from Google search into a business website to get a feel for the business, and learn more about what they’re offering. So obviously, including a link to your website is important for their online presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;93% of businesses have either missing or incorrect website information listed across all listings sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Only 7% of businesses have their website information correct across all listing sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Nearly half of small businesses don’t have a website &lt;a href=&quot;https://clutch.co/web-designers/resources/small-business-websites-2016-survey&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; title=&quot;Survey of small business websites&quot;&gt;(Clutch)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Blog/Screen-Shot-2017-08-23-at-8.40.06-AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Graph&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website accuracy by industry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a user can find your website, they’ll get a better impression of your business, and likely have a more positive experience. With nearly half of small businesses not having a website, you can make your business stand out on the SERP by including your website data in the listing information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other listing information to include&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your business vertical, there may be other pieces of information important for you to include in their online business listings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;basic-url&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Payment methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Brands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Holiday hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;Social profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;basic-li&quot;&gt;And more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more information you include across all listing sources and directories, the easier it will be for consumers to find your business and purchase your products and/or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Listings" /><summary type="html">Critical Data If you want to rank well in local search, you need consistent NAP data, website, hours, and more across all major listing directories. This is essential for search engines to validate you as a credible local business. The more accurate and consistent data there is about your business across the web, the more search engines will trust the validity of the business. And the more the search engines trust the business, the higher they will rank in local SERPs (Search Engine Results Page).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Listing_Sync_Pro_High_Res.png" /></entry></feed>